董卓主演脱口秀
欢迎各位来到《深夜秀》。
Welcome one and all to the late show.
我是你们的主持人，斯蒂芬·科尔伯特。
I'm your host, Stephen Colbert.
本周在...
This will go.
（欢呼和掌声）
Oh, my God.
你们可以对照我来检查一下日历。
You can check your calendars on me here.
This weekend was the official start of summer,
这个周末，夏天正式开始了，
我的观众们对此再清楚不过了。
as my audience knows all too well.
（欢呼和掌声）
Thank you.
谢谢你们。
谢谢你们，勇敢的灵魂们，感谢你们在外面
Thank you, you brave souls, for waiting outside
忍受着被天气频道描述为
and the humidity that the Weather Channel has described
“魔鬼的裤裆辣椒”般的湿热天气。 （注：“Devil's Trouser Chili”是主持人编造的俏皮话，形容极度湿热。）
as the Devil's Trouser Chili.
What else is going on?
（笑声）
还发生了什么？
What else is going on?
哦，对了。
Oh, right.
我们又在中东开战了。
We're at war in the Middle East again.
At least it sure looks that way.
至少看起来是这样。
（欢呼和掌声）
是啊。
Yeah.
而且这比任何人预想的都要快得多。
And it happened a lot sooner than anyone thought.
看，上周，特朗普的新闻秘书是这么说的。
See, last week, Trump's press secretary said this.
I have a message directly from the president, and I quote,
我有一条直接来自总统的消息，我引用一下，
“基于在不远的将来，
based on the fact that there's a substantial chance
与伊朗的谈判有很大可能性 会发生，也可能不会发生。”
of negotiations that may or may not take place
“与伊朗在不远的将来。”
with Iran in the near future.
“我将在未来两周内决定
I will make my decision whether or not
to go within the next two weeks.
是否要动手。”
那本来是完美的。
That would have been perfect for me,
对我来说，因为我们下周就要去度假了，
because we would have been on vacation next week,
那样我就完全不会知道发生了这些事。
and I wouldn't have known any of this was happening.
现在我得取消我
Now I'm going to have to cancel my reservation
在福尔多（伊朗核设施）的度假预约了。 （注：此为双关玩笑，福尔多是伊朗的核设施，不是度假胜地。）
that Samples Fordo.
（笑声）
但是在周六，就在周六，
But on Saturday, or just Saturday,
就在周六，特朗普震惊了
or just Saturday, and Saturday, Trump surprised the world,
全世界，宣布美国对伊朗的
announcing that the U.S. launch strikes
三个核设施发动了空袭。
on three Iranian nuclear facilities.
那么，我们是否面临着迫在眉睫的威胁？
Now, were we facing an imminent threat?
我不知道。
I don't know.
On one hand, Iran's slogan isn't life to America.
一方面，伊朗的口号可不是“美国万岁”。
But it's hard to trust Donald Trump
但另一方面，很难相信唐纳德·特朗普是那个
to be the one making these kinds of decisions.
能做这类决定的人。
It kind of feels like we're all in the backseat
感觉就像我们都坐在后座，
而我们的优步司机正在路上开斗气车。
while the Uber driver goes on a road rage.
Hey, hey, hey, buddy, we're in the car, too.
“嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿，老兄，我们也在车里呢，好吗？”
Okay?
“如果我们死了，可就没法给你五星好评了。”
And if we're dead, we can't give you five stars.
这是我的...
That's my...
这是我给司机评分的铁律。
That is my heart rule for rating drivers.
I'm dead.
我死了？
零分。
No.
活着到达？
Arrivalive?
我给五星。
I'm giving five.
周六晚些时候，特朗普向全国发表了几分钟的讲话，
Trump addressed the nation for a couple of minutes
并用一种极其古怪的方式结束了讲话。
later on Saturday night, and wrapped it up
in just the weirdest way.
“我只想感谢所有人，特别是，”
I want to just thank everybody, and in particular,
“上帝，我只想说，我们爱你，上帝，”
God, I want to just say, we love you, God,
and we love our great military, protect them.
“我们爱我们伟大的军队，保护他们。”
好吧，这是个美好的祝愿，你知道的，
Okay, it's a nice sentiment, you know?
But a weird way to say it.
但说的方式很奇怪。
“是的，我一直都是上帝虔诚的信徒。”
Yes, I have always been a devout believer in God.
“我们爱你，上帝。”
We love you, God.
“我知道我们关系不总是那么好，”
I know.
We haven't always been on the greatest terms
“自从我和那个在‘火焰林’里拿着‘波点叉’的家伙” （注：此为胡言乱语，模仿特朗普的讲话风格。）
since I made the deal with a guy with a polkae head
“做了交易之后。”
and the Flamenhoes.
“但重点是，你很酷，大家伙。”
But point is, you rock, big guy.
“好好上学。”
Stay in school.
“祝你暑假愉快，合十礼（Namaste）。”
Have a great summer, Namaste.
（笑声）
Namaste.
合十礼。
在周日投下炸弹后，
After the bombs were dropped on Sunday,
Trump posted this message with a key misspelling.
特朗普发布了这条信息，其中有一个关键的拼写错误。
The great B-2 pilots have just landed safely in Missouri.
“伟大的B-2飞行员们刚刚在密苏里州安全着陆。”
Thank you for a job.
“感谢你们的工作。”
Well done.
“干得好。”
“多纳克·J·特朗普（Donucked J. Trump），美利坚合众国总统。” （注：“Donucked”是“Donald”的拼写错误。）
Donucked, J-Trump.
President of the United States.
Yes.
是的。
好吧。
Okay.
耶。
Yes.
是的。
多纳克·J·特朗普，说得像个脑袋被“多纳克”了的人。
Donucked.
J-Trump, spoken like a man who got Donucked in Denog.
我们正在了解更多关于这次轰炸的细节，攻击计划。
We're learning more about the actual bombing, the attack plan.
It's codename Operation Midnight Hammer.
代号是“午夜战锤行动”。
And no, it's not porn.
不，这不是色情片。
LAUGHTER
（笑声）
Yet.
暂时还不是。
Here's what happened.
事情是这样的。
In order to avoid detection, the plan was carried out
为了避免被发现，计划由
by seven B-2 stealth bombers.
七架B-2隐形轰炸机执行。
And I'm... Is this true?
而且我，这是真的吗？
I'm told we have a picture of the stealth planes.
我被告知我们有隐形飞机的照片。 （注：此处为视觉笑话，屏幕上什么都没有。）
Wow.
哇。
Yeah.
它们真的很强。
They are good.
这些飞机携带了3万磅的炸弹，
The planes were carrying 30,000-pound bombs
known as bunker busters, officially called mobs,
被称为“地堡终结者”，官方名称是MOPs，
or massive ordinance penetrators.
即“巨型穿透弹”（Massive Ordinance Penetrators）。
这是自“战斧巡航恍惚弹”以来，
The most...
The most phallic-sounding weapon since the...
听起来最具阳具崇拜色彩的武器了。
Tomahawk cruise shunts.
So America spies must have truly compelling intelligence,
所以，美国的间谍们一定掌握了非常可信的情报，
indicating that Iran was close to building a nuclear weapon,
表明伊朗即将制造出核武器……
或者并没有，因为美国的间谍说伊朗并没有
or... or not, because America spies that Iran wasn't
在制造核武器。
building a nuclear weapon.
好吧。
Okay.
等等。
Hold on.
他们确定吗？
Are they sure?
也许我们的顶级间谍只是没时间做彻底的检查，
Maybe our top spies just didn't have time to do a thorough check
因为他们正忙着挂在双翼飞机上呢。 （注：暗指《碟中谍》电影情节。）
because they were too busy hanging off of a biplane.
LAUGHTER
But if the intelligence wasn't there, how did Trump decide
但如果情报不存在，
特朗普是如何决定是时候攻击伊朗的
it was time to attack Iran's nuclear program?
核计划的？
嗯，据一位政府高级官员说，
Well, according to a senior administration official,
it was based on a feeling...
这“基于总统的一种感觉”。
LAUGHTER
The president had.
CHEERING
If you are making a decision that could endanger the lives
如果你要做一个可能会
危及美国军队和平民生命的决定，
of American troops and civilians, help me out.
帮我一下。
Legal scholars, what does that require?
法律学者们，这需要什么？
MUSIC
谢谢你。
Thank you.
嘿，市长。
Hey, Mayor. Thank you.
谢谢你。
Hey, Mayor.
嘿，市长。
And thank you.
谢谢你。
CHEERING
感谢你的服务。
Thank you for your service.
也感谢那根手杖。
Thank you for that staff.
And remember, this is an America's first military industrial rodeo.
记住，这不是美国军工复合体的
第一次牛仔竞技。
I've been making jokes about whether or not we should be going
22年来，我一直在开玩笑
说我们是否应该去中东开战。
to war in the Middle East for 22 years.
I did jokes from the Middle East for the service people
我曾为中东的军人们讲过笑话，
who were sent into harm's way based on no credible intelligence.
他们就是因为那些不可信的情报而被派往险境的。
But I will say this.
但我得这么说。
I will say this, sure.
我得这么说。
当然，当然。
I will say this about the Bush administration.
关于布什政府，我得这么说。
At least they respected us enough to lie to us.
至少他们还尊重我们，知道要对我们撒谎。
Apparently, the Trump administration does not give a damn
显然，特朗普政府根本不在乎
what we think.
我们怎么想。
They're not presenting any evidence.
他们不提供任何证据。
Just come on, guys.
拜托，伙计们。
Just at least scare us a little.
至少也吓唬我们一下啊。
I missed the days when Colin Powell went to the UN Security Council
我怀念科林·鲍威尔去联合国安理会，
激情地挥舞着一管“乡村时光”牌
and passionately waved a tube of country-time lemonade powder.
柠檬水粉末的日子。 （注：讽刺2003年鲍威尔在联合国展示“伊拉克大规模杀伤性武器证据”——一小瓶白色粉末。）
I mean, just that much, just that much of the powder
我是说，就那么点粉末，就那么点，
could have refreshed everyone in that building.
就足够让那栋楼里的每个人都精神焕发了。
I mean, Trump should be out there telling us
特朗普应该站出来告诉我们，
that Iran is hiding 50 tons of mustard gas on a turkey farm
伊朗在火鸡农场藏了50吨芥子气，
or 50 tons of mustard turkey on a gas farm
或者在加油站农场藏了50吨芥末火鸡，
or human animal hybrids or anything.
或者人兽杂交体，或者随便什么都行。
Just sell it with sizzle.
至少卖力地宣传一下啊。
This is just lazy.
这简直是懒政。
It's got low production values.
制作水准太低了。
Imagine if the next Transformers movie was just like,
想象一下，如果下一部《变形金刚》电影就说：
you know what?
“你知道吗？”
I think we're just going to state cars in this one.
“我们觉得这部里就让它们保持汽车形态吧。”
What?
Put some effort in.
用点心好吗！
我知道。
I'm mad.
不，我生气了。
This isn't me, mad.
这不是我，生气。
What's going to happen next?
接下来会发生什么？
Whatever happens next, you know they're going to make
无论接下来发生什么，你都知道他们
会让JD·万斯上电视出洋相的。
JD Vance go on TV and embarrass himself.
Because here's what he said on Sunday to sell this war
因为这是他周日说的，
为了推销这场绝对不是战争的战争。
that is definitely not a war.
Is the United States now at war with Iran?
美国现在和伊朗开战了吗？
No, we're not at war with Iran.
不，我们没和伊朗开战。
John, we're at war with Iran's nuclear program.
约翰，我们是在和伊朗的核计划开战。
Nope, nope.
不，不。
That's not how it works.
事情不是这么运作的。
Honey, I'm not cheating on you with Stacey.
“亲爱的，我没有和史黛西出轨。”
I'm cheating on you with parts of Stacey.
“我是在和史黛西的某些部分出轨。”
Very selective.
非常有选择性。
（欢呼和掌声）
And yes.
是的。
And yes, we do call it Operation Midnight Hammer.
是的，我们确实把它叫做“午夜战锤行动”。
Then.
然后...
Pretty easy.
Okay.
真...
Then JD Sauntered Over to Press the Meet with Kristen Welker.
好吧。
然后JD慢悠悠地走到《媒体见面会》和克里斯汀·韦尔克聊天。
What do you say to members of Congress who say it was
你对那些说总统单方面行动
unconstitutional for the president to act unilaterally?
是违宪的国会议员
有什么要说的？
First of all, the president has clear authority to act
首先，总统有明确的权力
to prevent the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction.
采取行动防止大规模杀伤性武器的
扩散。
And the worst weapon of mass destruction of them all is nuclear.
而其中最糟糕的大规模杀伤性武器
就是核武器。
Debatable.
有待商榷。
From my money, the worst weapon of mass destruction
依我之见，最糟糕的大规模杀伤性武器
is the Taco Bell Triple Lupa.
是塔可钟的三层玉米饼。
（笑声）
If this all feels like deja vu, Vance promises this time is different.
如果这一切感觉似曾相识，
万斯保证，这次不一样。
I certainly empathize with Americans who are exhausted after 25 years
我当然同情那些在过去25年里
因中东的海外纠葛而疲惫不堪的美国人。
of foreign entanglements in the Middle East.
但不同之处在于，那时候，
But the difference is that back then we had dumb presidents.
我们有的是愚蠢的总统。
是的。
Yes.
Back then.
那时候...
他说得有道理。
He's got a point.
那时候，我们有的是愚蠢的总统。
Back then we had dumb presidents.
而现在，我们有的是“多纳克·J·特朗普”。
And now we have Donak J. Trump.
（笑声）
He is smart.
（欢呼和掌声）
还有另一个...
谢谢你们。
非常感谢。
You'll remember back in 2003, the US winner of Iraq
（欢呼和掌声）
with the specific goal of toppling Saddam Hussein.
他...
This time, Vance promises that's not the idea.
他很聪明。
（笑声）
Does the United States support Israel killing Iran's leader?
你会记得，在2003年，美国入侵伊拉克
的具体目标是推翻萨达姆·侯赛因。
Yes.
这一次，万斯保证，
想法不一样。
Yes.
美国是否支持以色列刺杀伊朗领导人？
嗯，看，那是以色列人自己的事，
Yes.
但我们的观点一直很明确，我们不希望政权更迭。
好的，响亮而明确，
Yes.
Well, look, that's up to the Israelis.
然后立刻被总统反驳了，他发帖说：
But our view has been very clear that we don't want a regime change.
“使用‘政权更迭’这个词在政治上是不正确的。”
Okay.
Great.
“但如果当前的伊朗政权不能让伊朗再次伟大...”
Loud and very clear and immediately contradicted by the president,
who posted,
it's not politely correct to use the term regime change.
“为什么不能有政权更迭呢？”
“让伊朗再次伟大（MIGA）。” （注：MIGA是“Make Iran Great Again”的缩写，戏仿特朗普的“MAGA”。）
（笑声）
Mega.
MIGA？
什么？
Mega, your whole damn thing is America first.
MIGA，你整个的核心理念是“美国优先”。
You can't just hand other countries your slogan.
你不能把你的口号随便送给其他国家。
That's like if McDonald's had an ad campaign that said,
那就好比麦当劳的广告说：
“我就喜欢，我喜欢的是汉堡王。”
I'm loving it, it being Burger King.
（笑声）
No.
不。
我生气了。
I'm mad.
不。
No.
God, bless it.
天哪，真要命。
（欢呼和掌声）
I'm sorry you had to see it.
抱歉，让你们看到了。
那是什么？
Let it out.
发泄出来，发泄出来。
今天，伊朗向两个美军基地发射了导弹，
Today, a Ron launched missiles against two U.S. bases,
其中一个在卡塔尔，但卡塔尔和特朗普政府
including one in Qatar, but both Qatar and the Trump administration
都提前得到了伊朗袭击的通知。
were made aware of the Iranian attack ahead of time.
所以谢天谢地，没有伤亡报告。
希望这就是结束了。
但谁知道呢？
因为在周六的空袭后，
伊朗警告说将会有“永恒的后果”。
永恒的后果。
这也是塔可钟三层玉米饼的口号。
我们今晚的节目很精彩。
我的嘉宾是伊德瑞斯·艾尔巴，以及来自U.S.E.的音乐嘉宾，
Zoran Mamdani和Brad Land。
稍后回来，我会告诉你们更多关于那场比赛的事。
只差几分钟。
（欢呼和掌声）